（寿樹(としき)）ウウッ…
You okay, kiddo?
（男Ａ）大丈夫か？ 小僧
今 医者を連れてくるからな
I'll bring you a doctor now.
しばらく我慢してろや
Hang in there for a bit.
（男Ａ）分かってると思うが
医者に余計なことは言うなよ
I think you know, but don't say
unnecessary things to him.
（男Ａ）俺たちも お前に
乱暴がしたいわけじゃないんや
It's not like we want to hurt you.
（入江(いりえ)）
彼は… 村の子じゃありませんね
He's not from the village.
I'm taking care of
an acquaintance's child.
（男Ａ）知り合いの子供を
預かってるんですよ
I see...
そうですか
Are you all right?
（入江）大丈夫ですか？
（寿樹）ウウッ…
痛いのは どの辺ですか？
Where does it hurt?
How did you get
this surgery scar?
（入江）
この手術の痕は どうしたんです？
（寿樹）
きょ… 去年の冬に交通事故で…
I-I got it after a car
accident last winter...
Accident?
事故？
- "Time Wasting" Chapter -
Episode 02: SIGN
When They Cry
Behind where I looked back
(who's there in the front)?
I raised my nails in the dark
(and slashed the night).
Raindrops become droplets of
blood and drip down the throat.
If you don't have
a place to go back to...
...then stop here on my finger.
I'll take you away
along with that finger.
To the unopenable
forest where cicadas cry.
You can't turn back anymore.
Akasaka-san, are you nervous?
（大石(おおいし)）赤坂(あかさか)さん 緊張してます？
（赤坂）いえ そんなことは…
No, not really.
大丈夫ですよ　雛見沢(ひなみざわ)地区へ
向かうと同僚に言い残してますし
It'll be okay.
I left a note that we're heading
to the Hinamizawa district.
Well, of course, it's better
than not being prepared at all.
（大石）まあ もちろん―
油断をしないに越したことは
ありませんがねえ
梨花(りか)ちゃん？
Rika-chan?
（大石）
この先を抜けると高津戸(たかつど)地区です
The Takatsudo
district is past here.
Please don't forget
to take off your safety gear.
安全装置 外すのを
忘れないでくださいよ
（大石）数年前までは
人が住んでいたんですがね
Until a few years ago,
people were actually living here.
（赤坂）こんな へんぴなとこで
財布が発見されたんですか？
The wallet was found
in such a remote place?
（大石）村人には 山の中に
畑を持ってる連中がいましてね
There are some villagers who
have fields in the mountains.
Such people pass through here
in the mornings and evenings.
そういう連中は
朝晩 ここを通りますから
ここを徒歩で？
Pass through here on foot?
まさか！
行ける所までは車で行くんですよ
No way.
They go by car
as far as they can.
They found the wallet
on the ground while driving?
車で走ってて
落ちてる財布を発見したんですか？
The finder happened
to have a stomachache...
拾った人間は
たまたま おなかが痛くなって―
...and left the car to take
a dump in the bushes.
ちょいと茂みで用を足そうと
車を降りた
It seems that's how it was found.
それで 見つけたらしいですよ
I see.
そうですか
Irie-sensei! Hello.
（大石）入江先生 こんにちは
大石さんじゃありませんか
If it isn't Oishi-san.
We meet in an unusual place.
珍しい所で お会いしますね
That's what I want to say.
そりゃ こっちのセリフですよ
And what brings you
to a place like this?
先生のほうこそ
どうしたんです？ こんな所で
A house call.
（入江）ちょっとした往診です
Oh no. An emergency?
（大石）ありゃ… 急患とか？
No.
いえ それが…
Well, there's something
that concerns me.
ちょっと気になることが…
（大石･赤坂）えっ？
（男Ｂ）あっ… 営林署の人間か？
Forest service field office?
いや 警察(サツ)やな
No, police.
（男Ａ）時間稼いでる
小僧連れて 裏から抜けえや
I'll buy some time.
Take the kid and
leave from the back.
（男Ｂ）わ… 分かった
G-Got it!
Pardon me!
（大石）ごめんください
Hello, this is the police.
（大石）どうも 警察ですが
ちょっと よろしいですか？
Do you have a second?
（ノック）
はいはい 今開けます
Yes, yes.
I'm opening it right now.
（男Ｂ）ハァハァ…
（赤坂）止まれ！ 警察だ！
Stop! Police!
（つまずく音）
ウワッ！
ヤーッ！
（男Ｂ）ウワッ！
A-Are you Toshiki Inukai?
い… 犬飼(いぬかい)寿樹君かい？
Yes.
Who the hell are you?
（男Ｂ）何じゃ？ お前(めえ)は
Don't resist anymore.
（赤坂）これ以上 抵抗するな
おとなしく降参しろ
Just give up.
（男Ｂ）てめえこそ
小僧をこっちへ よこすんだ！
You jerk, hand over the kid!
Backup will arrive shortly.
There's no escape!
もうじき 応援が到着する
貴様らに逃げ場などない
大石さん！
Oishi-san!
な… 大石さんは？
（男Ａ）ああ？
Where's Oishi-san?
落としたら 泡吹いとったよ
ハハハハッ…
When I dropped him,
he was blowing bubbles.
Damn.
くそ…
ウウッ…
（寿樹）おじさん 大丈夫？
Are you okay?
大丈夫…
I'm fine.
あんまりナメてんと
容赦しねえぞ！
If you underestimate me
too much, I'll show no mercy!
（雪絵(ゆきえ)）
待ってますから この子と一緒に
I'll be waiting for
you with this baby.
ウワッ！ アア…
大石さん！
Oishi-san!
王手飛車取りってところですかね
Now this is
kind of like checkmate.
（男Ａ）ず… ずらかれ
L-Let's get out of here.
大石さん！
Oishi-san!
ムリですね 私１人じゃ とても
It's impossible.
I can't do it by myself.
And they know it well.
あいつらも よく分かってる
（赤坂）えっ？
（大石）逃げてる背中を
警官は撃てませんからねえ
Policemen can't shoot people
running away in the backs.
いやぁ 私も退職金が惜しいもんで
Well, I want
my retirement bonus too.
君が犬飼大臣のお孫さん？
（寿樹）は… はい
You're Cabinet Minister
Inukai's grandson?
Y-Yes.
アア…
こりゃ でかい事件になるかなぁ
This may become
a huge problem.
どうせ トカゲのシッポ切りに
なるんでしょうけどね フフフッ…
In any case, there's probably
going to be a scapegoat.
（倒れる音）
おっと！
Wha?
あ… 赤坂さん！
Akasaka-san!
Mamoru Akasaka
大丈夫ですか？
Are you all right?
（入江）弾は貫通していますが
24時間は特に安静にしてください
The bullet penetrated cleanly,
but please rest for 24 hours.
You're from back then...
（赤坂）あのときの…
（入江）入江と申します よろしく
My name's Irie.
Pleased to meet you.
（入江）
何かありましたら お呼びください
If you need anything,
please let me know.
いかがですか？
How are you?
（赤坂）慣れないことをしたんで
全身がボロボロです
I did something I'm not used to,
so my entire body is worn out.
犯人たちは逮捕されましたか？
Were the suspects arrested?
- Unfortunately...
- The minister's grandson?
残念ながら
大臣の孫は？
（大石）大丈夫
He's fine.
Being cared for at the station.
署で保護しています
（赤坂）そうですか
I see.
（大石）あ～ それと
もうひとつ お知らせが…
Oh, there's one more
thing I have to tell you.
I heard the minister said he's
freezing the Hinamizawa dam.
（大石）大臣が雛見沢ダム計画を
凍結すると言ったとか
（赤坂）
凍結… 中止ってことですか？
Freezing? It's being cancelled?
It probably means that
in exchange for the hostage...
人質と引き換えに ダム計画を
撤回したということでしょう
...he withdrew the dam plan.
In other words, the minister and
suspects' deal is completed.
（大石）つまり
大臣と犯人の取り引きが―
成立したということですなぁ
そんな！ それじゃ…
But... Then...
私たちが頑張らなくても―
Then even if we hadn't tried,
Toshiki-kun would've been freed.
寿樹君は 解放されていたと
いうことでしょうな
（大石）赤坂さん
Akasaka-san, there may be a force
more powerful than we think...
この事件 もしかすると
私たちが考えている以上の力が…
いや 組織が
動いているのかもしれませんよ
No, an organization
at work behind all this.
（赤坂）どういうことですか？
What do you mean?
Well, this is entirely
my own thinking, but...
いえね
これは全く私の推論ですがね
Those two we tackled with...
あの取っ組み合いをした２人…
どう考えても 訓練された人間です
（赤坂）訓練？
...were certainly trained
no matter how we look at it.
Trained?
そこいらのチンピラが―
It's hard to believe that a street
thug could pull off such a scuffle.
あんな立ち回りが
できるとは思えないんですよ
ハァ… そう言われれば
Speaking of which...
Yes, his shooting
skill was also precise.
そう　射撃の腕も正確でした
Well, everything
is a mystery now.
（大石）まあ 今となっては
全てが霧の中ですがね ハハハッ…
Irie Medical Clinic
Cigarettes
何なんだ？ これ
What is this?
What's going on?
（赤坂）どういうことだ？
なんで みんな…
Why are they all...
君は…
You're...
（梨花）ケガ人が病院を
抜け出しては いけないのですよ
Injured people shouldn't
sneak out of the hospital.
（赤坂）
もしかして 君が電話のコードを？
Did you cut the phone cords?
かけても
赤坂が悲しくなるだけなのです
Even if you called, it'd only
make you sad, Akasaka.
Me?
私が？
にぱ～！
Ni-pa~.
Go quietly back to the hospital?
おとなしく
病院へ帰れってことかい？
That would be better.
それがいいのですよ
病院への道は分かりますですか？
Do you know
the way to the hospital?
Yeah.
Your house is this way too?
梨花ちゃん家(ち)も
こっちの方向なのかい？
なのですよ
Yes.
（赤坂）そう
I see.
Oppose the dam! Be ashamed!
Protect Hinamizawa!
Oh, right.
（赤坂）ああ そっか
確か この神社が
梨花ちゃんの家だったよね？
Isn't this shrine your house?
Well, something like that.
まあ そんなものです
今日は お祭りの日なのです
It's festival day today.
お祭り？
Festival?
（梨花）雛見沢村の唯一のお祭り
綿流しのお祭りなのです
It's Hinamizawa's one and only
festival, the Cotton Drifting Festival.
綿流し？
Cotton Drifting?
祭りなんて名ばかりの
つまらないものですよ
Just like the name,
the festival itself is boring.
見ますですか？
Would you like to see?
Yeah.
（男性）
こっちにも酒持ってきてくれ！
See? A boring festival, right?
（梨花）
ねっ？ つまんないお祭りでしょう
ハハハッ… これは
確かに お祭りには見えないな
This certainly doesn't
look like a festival.
こんなのは 全然
綿流しのお祭りじゃないのです
This stuff isn't even near being
the festival of cotton drifting.
あっ… ハァ…
When you look down like this,
this village looks calm.
こうして眺めると―
この村も
のどかそうに見えますです
君は この村は絶対に
ダムに沈むことはないと―
You said that the dam definitely
wouldn't submerge this village.
そう断言したね？
なぜ そう思ったんだい？
Why did you think so?
I don't understand difficult topics.
ボクには 難しいことは
よく分かりませんです
でも 良かったじゃないか
（梨花）何がですか？
But you should be glad.
About what?
At least peace will now
return to this village.
（赤坂）少なくとも
これで この村に平和が戻るよ
（梨花）平和が？ この村に？
Peace? To this village?
Yeah.
Even though every year from now,
gruesome, bloody things will occur?
これから毎年 血生ぐさいことが
起きるのに …ですか？
In a few years, I will be killed.
（梨花）
あと何年かすると 私は殺されるの
Killed?
（赤坂）“殺される”って…
You? Why?
梨花ちゃんが？ どうして？
This has been decided.
（梨花）これは決まっていること
D-Decided?
Who decides such a thing?
（赤坂）き… 決まっているって
誰が そんなことを決めるんだい？
This place is full of those who
don't care about people's lives.
ここは 人の命を何とも
思わない連中で いっぱいだもの
これを伝えても
何も変わらないかもしれないけど
Even if I tell you this,
nothing may change.
でも 水面(みなも)に映った“死”という
月をかき消すためなら―
But erasing the moon called death
reflected on the water's surface...
...by casting a pebble
may be possible.
小石を投じることも
あるかもしれない
What are you talking about?
一体 何の話を？
When They Cry
（大石）赤坂さん！
Akasaka-san!
ハハハハッ… 何年ぶりでしょう？
How many years was it?
大石さん ご無沙汰しております
Oishi-san, long time no see.
One day, a few years
after the kidnapping...
（赤坂）誘拐事件から
数年がたった ある日―
...I reunited with Oishi-san.
私は 大石氏との再会を果たした
大石氏は定年後 母親の
郷里に当たる札幌(さっぽろ)に引っ越していた
After retiring, he moved to his
mother's hometown of Sapporo.
私が
大石氏に会いたいと思ったのは―
I felt I wanted to see him to
confirm something if nothing else.
あることを確かめたかったからに
ほかならない
Entrance Ceremony
美雪(みゆき)は 死んだ雪絵の
おなかから生まれた―
Miyuki was born from
the late Yukie's womb.
She's Yukie reincarnated.
雪絵の生まれ変わりなのだ
Yes, my wife, Yukie...
そう 私の妻 雪絵は
あの綿流しの祭りの夜に死んだ
...died on that night of
the Cotton Drifting Festival.
I heard Yukie would go up to
the roof and gaze at the sunset...
雪絵は毎日 夕方になると―
屋上に上がり
夕日を眺めていたそうだ
...every day in the late afternoon.
And going back to her room, she
lost her footing on the stairway...
そして 部屋へ戻る途中の階段で
足を踏み外し…
たまたま
運の悪い角度で強く打ちつけた
...and happened to land
hard at an unlucky angle.
親しくなった看護婦に
雪絵は こう言っていたそうだ
I heard Yukie said this to a nurse
she had gotten close to...
..."When he's far away
under the same sky...
“あの人が
遠くへ出かけているときは―”
“同じ空の下で あの人の無事を
祈っていてあげたい”と…
...I want to pray for his safety."
Did you cut the phone cords?
（赤坂）
もしかして 君が電話のコードを？
かけても
赤坂が悲しくなるだけなのです
Even if you called, it'd only
make you sad, Akasaka.
そう
あれは雪絵の死を悟った梨花が―
Yes, that was Rika, who
had discerned Yukie's death...
...pitying me.
私を哀れみ したことだったのだ
Go back to Tokyo.
（梨花）東京へ帰れ
（赤坂）えっ？
Otherwise,
you'll regret it very much.
でないと
ひどく後悔することになる
Entrance Ceremony
If I had known the outcome...
もしも
私が その結果を知っていて―
If I had known the outcome...
...and gone back to Tokyo,
dropping my work as she said...
彼女の言うとおり 仕事を投げ出し
東京に戻っていたら…
...Yukie's death
might've been prevented.
雪絵の死は
避けられていたのかもしれない
Kanie Onsen Hotel
Sure.
いいですよ
赤坂さんの言うとおり―
As you said...
...let's assume Rika Furude was
a prophet who knew the future.
古手(ふるで)梨花は
未来が分かる予言者だったとします
ハァ～ッ…
Then why couldn't she
predict that major disaster?
なら なぜ あの大災害が
予知できなかったんです？
Yes. The end of June, 1983.
（赤坂）そう 昭和(しょうわ)58年６月末
鬼ヶ淵(おにがふち)沼より
猛毒の火山ガスが噴出して―
Toxic volcanic gas from Onigafuchi
Swamp hit the village at midnight...
深夜の村を直撃
村人が全滅するという
未曽有の大災害が起きた
...wiping out all villagers.
An unprecedented catastrophe.
雛見沢地区は
今でも封鎖されている
The Hinamizawa district
is still blockaded even now.
Well, but...
（大石）まあ でも…
ハァ～ッ…
Oyashiro-sama's reincarnation,
Rika Furude was killed...
オヤシロさまの生まれ変わりである
古手梨花が殺されたので
村が オヤシロさまの怒りに触れて
...so the village
instigated his anger.
それで 沼から沼気が湧き出して
And so noxious gas erupted from
the swamp, wiping out the village.
村を死滅させたんじゃないかって
It's a fact that this was said
among the Hinamizawa survivors...
（大石）そういう話が―
確かに雛見沢出身の
生存した人間たちの間で―
まことしやかに
ささやかれていたのは事実ですがね
...as though it were true.
あっ 失礼
Excuse me,
did you just say killed?
（赤坂）今 “殺された”と
おっしゃいましたか？
Yes.
（大石）ええ… 大災害の当日…
On the day of
the catastrophe, around noon...
昼ごろに
神社へ訪れた村の老人たちが―
...elderly villagers visiting
the shrine discovered her corpse.
古手梨花の死体を発見しました
他殺…
（大石）うん
A homicide?
Naked and barefoot.
（大石）全裸でハダシ
分かったのは
薬物で昏睡(こんすい)させられてから―
What we know is that after
a drug-induced coma...
...she was carried there,
her abdomen was opened...
あの場所へ運ばれ 腹部を切開
...and her internal organs
were intentionally pulled out.
意図的に
臓器を引きずり出されていました
Coma?
昏睡？ では 開腹は死後ではなく…
Then the incision
wasn't made after death?
It's as I thought...
（赤坂）
やはり そうだったんですか…
（大石）“やはり”？
As you thought?
（赤坂）
大石さんは この連続怪死事件…
Oishi-san, what's your take on
these serial, mysterious deaths...
オヤシロさまのたたりを
どう捉えていますか？
...and Oyashiro-sama's curse?
Akasaka-san,
you can only say that now...
赤坂さん そりゃ ５年も続いて―
派手な最後があった今だから
言えることですよ
...because it went on for five
years and had the worst ending.
Back then, those incidents
happened by chance...
あの当時は 事件が毎年
偶然にも綿流しの日に起こる
...every year on
Cotton Drifting day.
We all felt like, "I hope
nothing happens this year."
“今年は起きないといいな”なんて
感じだったんです
I don't think it was by chance.
偶然じゃないと思います
あの少女は 全てを知っていました
That little girl knew everything.
Rika Furude?
古手梨花がですか？
（赤坂）はい
Yes, she predicted all the serial,
mysterious deaths to me.
あの子は 私に連続怪死事件の
全てを予言してみせました
（赤坂）そう
今回の私の旅のいちばんの目的は…
Right, the primary purpose
of my trip this time...
Hinamizawa Serial
Mysterious Deaths
...was to find the link between the
Oyashiro-sama serial murders...
オヤシロさま連続殺人事件と―
それを予言した古手梨花の
関係を知ることだった
Hinamizawa Serial
Mysterious Deaths
...and Rika Furude,
who had predicted them.
Then does that mean all
the scenarios were prepared...
とすると 連続怪死事件は―
発生の前年には
もう全てシナリオが用意されていた
...a year before
the serial, mysterious deaths?
…ということですかな？
And as in those scenarios,
Rika Furude was killed.
（赤坂）そして その予告どおり
古手梨花は殺されました
The girl knew
about her own death.
彼女は
自分の死を知っていたのです
Then why didn't
Rika Furude run away?
（大石）なら 古手梨花は どうして
逃げ出さなかったんですかねえ？
（大石）なぜ あらがわずに
自分の死を受け入れたんです？
Why did she accept her death
without trying to avoid it?
彼女は なぜ誰かにＳＯＳを
発しなかったんでしょうか？
Why didn't she send out
an SOS to someone?
She did.
ありました
えっ？
（赤坂）彼女は 確かに―
She definitely was sending
an SOS calling for help.
ＳＯＳを…
救いを求めていたんです
この私に…
To me.
（梨花）来年の今日…
On this day next year...
Yes, on this day in June 1979...
そう 昭和54年の６月の今日
...the dam site
manager will be killed.
ダム工事の現場監督が殺される
（赤坂）
えっ？ “殺される”って…
Killed?
体中をバラバラに引き裂かれて
捨てられる
His body will be
dismembered and thrown away.
Dismembered?
Following that year,
on this day in June 1980...
（梨花）
その翌年(よくとし)の昭和55年の６月の今日
沙都子(さとこ)の両親が
崖から突き落とされて殺される
...Satoko's parents will be
pushed off a cliff and killed.
Satoko?
沙都子？
その翌年の昭和56年の６月の今日
The following year,
on this day in June 1981...
...my parents will die.
私の両親が死ぬ
Further, the following year,
on this day in June 1982...
更に
翌年の昭和57年の６月の今日―
...Satoko's mean aunt will get
her head cracked and be killed.
沙都子の意地悪な叔母が
頭を割られて殺される
そして 次の年
昭和58年の６月の今日
And in the next year,
on this day in June 1983...
あるいは その数日後か…
...or maybe a few days later...
...I will be killed.
私が殺される
君が？
You?
If all the deaths
happen as predicted...
全ての死が予定調和なら…
...is the last death
also in the prediction?
最後の死もまた 予定のうちなの
でも…
ならば これは一体 誰の予定なの？
But in that case,
whose prediction is it?
What are you trying to...
君は 一体 何を…
I want to live happily.
（梨花）私は幸せに生きたい
望みは それだけ
That's my only wish.
I want to spend fun days
surrounded by my favorite friends.
大好きな友人たちに囲まれて
楽しく日々を過ごしたい
That's all.
それだけなのに…
それ以上の何も望んでいないのに…
I am not wishing
for anything more, but...
梨花ちゃん…
Rika-chan...
I don't want to die.
死にたくない
（赤坂）雛見沢地区の封鎖は
今年も まだ解けていない
Even until this year...
...the Hinamizawa district
blockade still has not been lifted.
To get my happiness,
I had done everything...
...but had done nothing
to be blamed and accused of.
The sound of footsteps
became louder every day.
Then I noticed the fact
there was no time.
I was a believer in life,
to be myself always.
And was asking
whether I would be alive.
Give me a reason
why not to adopt in this way.
Or judge me to be guilty
of so many incurable sins.
Tell me why or why not?
Complaining way too much.
Maybe I overlooked
something fatal for me.
Preview
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
出会うのは 優しさへの代償
Preview
What meets is
the compensation for kindness.
落ちるのは 悲しみへの迷路
What falls is
the maze to sadness.
焦がすのは 恨みへの思い
What burns are
thoughts toward vengeance.
When They Cry.
「ひぐらしのなく頃に」
"Eye Opening" Chapter,
Episode 1: FIRST LOVE.
- "Eye Opening" Chapter -
Episode 01: FIRST LOVE
"Eye Opening" Chapter,
Episode 1: FIRST LOVE.
あなたは信じられますか？
- "Eye Opening" Chapter -
Episode 01: FIRST LOVE
Can you believe it?